Yes, so someone asking that how to join Microsoft so
let me record this.
OK, let's get started and hi everyone I'm Anduin.
I'm a software engineer, and here at Microsoft.
So yeah let's put this on.
I'm currently working on the Microsoft 365 team and
focusing on the data center deployment of the Microsoft 365
backend systems.
And yeah, Microsoft is an American technology company and headquarters
at Redmond and Washington and it develops software devices and
related services which is best known products like Windows 10
Office and Azure Cloud. It also provides other services like
hardware like.
Surface and Xbox. Also, Microsoft have developed plenty of famous
developing tools like Visual Studio.
Yeah, so I joined and then worked as a full
time employee and Microsoft for about one year and have some
fantastic adventures that I can share.
Yes, for most people is implying that working on Microsoft
and not so busy nor tiring, well for us we
believe that we can have a balance between work and
life since most of our products have benefits and run
for more than 30 years.
So we're using that under that pressure to open new
markets and serve new customers every day.
So working on Microsoft usually means that you can have.
You can enjoy your daily life while contributing to one
of the largest companies that change everybody's life.
Oh, I currently located in China.
I live in Suzhou, a beautiful City,
A beautiful and relaxing city with lots of attractions and near Shanghai.
So I live in Suzhou while
The person I report my work item.
My work progress to is living in America so it's
just like a professor.
He gave me a direction of development and I need
to inform my work progress every week.
It provides a great freedom,
a great flexibility to arrange your own time that,
like I usually wake up at 11:00 o'clock in the
morning and starting work at 2:00 o'clock PM so.
Yeah, if we can have all my necessary work items
finished early so I can stop working early.
I yeah working here. Just like doing homework,
in the college that if you finish all your
homework and get out to play yes so I can
have plenty of time.
So for club activities or physical exercise or maybe like
making videos like this.
Yeah so let's get back to the title.
How can you like a new developer or student to
have a chance to join Microsoft and what you need
to learn?
An can you started from our recruitment roles?
Since Microsoft is a technology company,
almost every position for Microsoft requires a bachelor degree in
computer science or related majors.
So if you want to say I don't qualify for
a bachelors degree in software engineering,
then sorry, the only choice left to you is to
get a master degree back in the school.
Yeah last from my workmates have done on that path
or you may mention that your school might not be
in the best class and if we can still get
a chance. My answer is don't worry bout that.
It depends of course that we providing possibilities for every
person.
If your other professional skills and experience are so solid
that we may still consider hiring someone from a school
that does not sound such famous.
And yeah Microsoft large company that requires you to talk
with others to solve problems together and it requires excellent
communication skills.
Of course in English, so usually we have about three
to four meetings every week.
Yeah, which requires you to listen to talk and will
write English in emails.
And also in code reviews with you ask you to
communicate to speak in English during all those code reviews,
including the interview. So English is so important but actually
English level of mine is enough.
I'm not a native English speaker and I learned English
from only a Chinese-speaking school.
But compared with vocabulary and grammar,
we hope you can express your ideas bravely more.
I like my English not excellent of course,
but it's far enough for me to express my ideas
or do some simple presentations.
That's fun, that's enough. Not so high.
Yeah, yeah, you can express.
This is enough. And of course,
the most necessary part for candidates is a solid knowledge
of data structure and algorithms.
We actually don't require you to write C# before
we don't even need you to use Windows.
You can use any operating systems.
Installing any editors, writing any programming language you like.
But what we must examine is that you must have
a profound understanding of the data you want to manipulate.
And this requires you to make an intense accumulation in
mathematics an all rhythms.
Participating in algorithm competitions or frequent practice algorithm questions will
help improve your written skills.
Yes, which will greatly significantly benefit you during the interview.
And yeah, you really there gonna be four to five
turns of interviewing where we examine your algorithm skills.
We don't need that to be so extremes.
For example, if you don't know the red black tree,
you no worries is fun.
Absolutely fun for me. I don't know the black,
red black tree. What he said you can just suggest
the interview with the change of question to easier and
easier question when you really just ask some simple questions
like can you rotate a matrix without allocating new space
a square matrix?
I will try that if you can finish a middle
level question in less than 20 minutes,
you have a high possibility already have a high possibility
pass interview.
Yeah, if you can pass it all those five times
you already about to join in.
So yeah, not only the algorithm at last,
that also would be better if you have incredible experience
including working for years in those related areas or Community
contribution.
That is to say, yeah.
If I have a famous project on GitHub or have
an account on Stack Overflow with a high score or
something like this that have some open source contributions,
yeah, that is also counted.
We will consider that. And I also suggest you to
host A blog of your own so that you can
write technology articles everyday on your own blog.
At that will not only benefit your interview,
but also it is a record of what you have
learned.
So in brief, there are four targets for you.
One is bachelor's degree in computer science,
the second one is excellent English communication scale skills.
The third one is solid algorithm knowledge and the 4th
one is technology related experience.
All those four targets are required,
so yeah, if you already already ready in all those
forests and you're prepared to have an interview to join
Microsoft so I can help you reference ISH and what
you need to do currently to open this link careers.microsoft.com
and find a position you like,
find a job position, you can search any positions here
we open currently in at Microsoft and then you,
after you funding a position,
please send me the link,
send me the URL. To my email,
my email address is undoing.xe@microsoft.com.
And doing that actually at microsoft.com.
And please write your title reference request.
Also please attach your GitHub account and LinkedIn account.
Or maybe Stackoverflow account. Yes,
hopefully after I can provide you a reference soon and
then you can have an interview in about one to
two weeks.
Yeah, considering the impact of COVID-19,
Microsoft is now working remotely that even in China we
here we don't have to go to the office every
day.
While we support remote working life,
I also don't suggest you to try a position out
of your country which have a lower possibility to pass.
So if it is possible,
please consider a job within your own country.
And yeah, I'm always looking forward to your success message.
Microsoft is always a warm and welcoming family that we're
always expecting you guys.
Everybody gathered here. We just hired.
One target is One Direction to solve problems together and
you know we we don't know who we might be
collaborating that those persons might from different nations.
Different colors, different religions, yeah,
but we just gathered here as a family and solving
problems together.
Yeah, of course, no matter if you want to join
Microsoft,
please do subscribe to this channel here.
And yes, thanks for watching.
Bye.